Richard Morre

6429,Miami Ave, Glen Burnie,MD,US ↑
+1 571-261-6937 ↓
petepiao1017@gmail.com ✓
https://www.linkedin.com/in/richard820/in

Senior Machine Learning Engineer with 8+ years of experience in application design, development, testing, and deployment. Led a technical team of 5 members at *Curatat* and responsible for implementing CI/CD for data engineering and machine learning platform. Completed more than 10 products and made 20M+ \$ for several employers. Abilities to identify, understand, and translate program requirements into sustainable, advanced technical solutions through Python, C#, C++, JavaScript, and other programs for continuous improvement of Al technologies.

Work Experience

Team Leader/Senior Machine Learning Engineer | Curata Botson, MS, US

2021.1 - 2022.12

- Optimized compiler and accelerate its speed to 3.8 times using AI (fully-Bayesian generative network).
- Led a team of 5 junior machine learning engineers in building a model, which could detect 80 different classes in satellite images (xview1 dataset) using Pytorch and Yolov8
- Established brain injury detection system using Python, Docker, OpenCV, AWS Amplify, S3, Lambda, SageMaker and IoT. Also usded SVM regression algorithm for forecasting the position of pupils.
- Developed a custom fire detection model with **92% accuracy**, which was trained on an open-source dataset using a Resnet with a size constraint.
- Developed and trained an unsupervised model which takes free text as input, applies the LDA algorithm to it, and returns the topics contained in that text using Python/Gensim
- Developed a model using Python/Deepspeech to take speech audio along with some words and to return the timestamp of those words in the audio.

Machine Learning Engineer | Fronteo, US,

New York, US

2019.1 - 2020.11

- Architecting our Customer Activity Tracking System that collected, computed, and served user intent signals for web
 personalization. This system powered personalization features that increased our checkout conversion rate by 10%.
 This system was developed using Python, Terraform, AWS Lambda, AWS DynamoDB, and AWS API Gateway.
- Building a lead-to-contract algorithm that used web interaction data to identify high-intent customers. The sales strategies powered by this algorithm generated an additional 1000 deposits per year. The algorithm was built using Python, Fast API, Scikit-Learn, and AWS DynamoDB.
- Devised a face mask detection with real time videos using Python, OpenCV, Yolov2 with 98% accuracy.
- Established the Brain Injury Detection System using Python, Docker, OpenCV, AWS Amplify, AWS Lambda, AWS S3.

Full Stack Engineer / Junior Machine Learning Engineer | MEGVII Beijing, China

2014.10 - 2018.12

- Authored two patents on a chatbot for psychological support and emotion analysis of text, respectively (Registered).
- Improved web performance (faster load times, smaller bundle sizes). Established reusable & responsive React chart components using D3.js that support interactive visualizations of data and analysis.
- Built React front-end and Node.js Backend admin dashboard for complex data table visualization with user-friendly searching features.
- Built React front-end and Node.js Backend admin dashboard for complex data table visualization with user-friendly searching features.

Education

Master's Degree in Mathematics and Computer Science | Boston University

2010.5 - 2014.5

- GPA:3.7/4.00
- Concentrations: Al | ML | DL | Applied mathematics | Algorithms | RESTful API

Skills

- Machine Learning
- Statistics
- Optimization
- Computer Vision
- MLOps
- Compiler
- NLP
- OpenCV
- Python (Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-learn)
- Scala
- Java
- Tensorflow,PyTorch,Keras
- Big Data(Hadoop,Spark,Hive)
- SQL(MySQL,PostgreSQL,Oracle)
- NoSQL(MongoDB,DynomoDB)
- Backend Framework(Flask,Django)

- Data Structure & Algorithm
- CI/CD
- Jenkins, Docker
- Git
- GCP (Kubernetes, Vertex AI)
- AWS(S3,EC2,SageMaker,Amplify,Kinesis, Airflow)
- Agile Methodologies
- Microsoft Azure
- Apache Kafka, Apache Beam
- C/C++
- Javascript
- Frontend Framework(React.js,Angular.js)
- Pruning
- Chip Architecture
- Quantization

Language

- English (Native)
- Chinese (Native)[mandarin]